<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-05T16:55:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Abstract</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/abstract.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Abstract" /><published>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/abstract</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/abstract.html">&lt;p&gt;Low-power and wide-area (LPWA) technologies have become popular in various IoT services, mainly due to their low power and long communication range characteristics. However, LPWA still suffers from limited coverage and reliability issues, especially in an urban area where line-of-sight (LOS) communication is hard to achieve. The problem gets worsening in massive IoT environments as LPWA is vulnerable to the collision because of its long transmission time and unsophisticated Aloha-based MAC, which gets worse as the number of contending devices increases. Placing a relay forwarder between end-devices and gateway is introduced in some studies to extend coverage and to enhance communication reliability of LPWA. However, most previous studies adopt fixed-routing protocols for the relay. These fixed path approaches are vulnerable to the dynamicity of wireless propagation and make little use of multiple receptions, so it may easily lead to unnecessary forwarding that may raise collisions aggravating overall reliability and performance. We propose an opportunistic routing protocol for LPWA forwarders to make good use of multiple receptions. To suppress unnecessary forwarding, we adopt an on-demand/feedback message mechanism that is used by relays to determine whether to forward a packet or not. We also employ a network coding in generating forwarding packets in relays to increase the reliability and throughput further. As header overhead of network coding may exceed the size limitation of the LPWA packet, we use a header compression technique to encounter it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Index Terms—LPWA, unnecessary forwarding, on-demand, opportunistic forwarding, network coding, header overhead.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Low-power and wide-area (LPWA) technologies have become popular in various IoT services, mainly due to their low power and long communication range characteristics. However, LPWA still suffers from limited coverage and reliability issues, especially in an urban area where line-of-sight (LOS) communication is hard to achieve. The problem gets worsening in massive IoT environments as LPWA is vulnerable to the collision because of its long transmission time and unsophisticated Aloha-based MAC, which gets worse as the number of contending devices increases. Placing a relay forwarder between end-devices and gateway is introduced in some studies to extend coverage and to enhance communication reliability of LPWA. However, most previous studies adopt fixed-routing protocols for the relay. These fixed path approaches are vulnerable to the dynamicity of wireless propagation and make little use of multiple receptions, so it may easily lead to unnecessary forwarding that may raise collisions aggravating overall reliability and performance. We propose an opportunistic routing protocol for LPWA forwarders to make good use of multiple receptions. To suppress unnecessary forwarding, we adopt an on-demand/feedback message mechanism that is used by relays to determine whether to forward a packet or not. We also employ a network coding in generating forwarding packets in relays to increase the reliability and throughput further. As header overhead of network coding may exceed the size limitation of the LPWA packet, we use a header compression technique to encounter it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Motivation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/motivation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Motivation" /><published>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/motivation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/motivation.html">&lt;h4&gt;3.0.1  Preventing unnecessary forwarding&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/master_thesis/assets/img/problem.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the side effects of the forwarder mechanism is unnecessary forwarding. Unnecessary forwarding uses network resources, which prevents the transmission from the legitimate packet. Thus, leading to performance degradation. As LPWA already offers broader coverage, the forwarder mechanism is only useful in certain conditions (see figure 1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, forwarders in LPWA should consider unnecessary forwarding if the gateway already receives the packet. To prevent this, we present an on-demand mechanism by such feedback messages like SACK acknowledgment contains all currently received packets to the relay. Therefore, relay only forward the missing packets after receiving the packets state from the network server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; 3.0.2  Reliability in uncertain wireless conditions &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/master_thesis/assets/img/wirelessconditions.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the wireless link is unstable, figure 2 shows possible transmission and reception between end-devices, relays, and gateway. Suppose that R1 and R2 receives the message, while R3 fails due to the propagation problem. If fixed-path routing assumes that R3 is the best forwarder, the packet cannot be delivered to the destination. Thus, we require re-transmission from the sender again. However, unnecessary retransmission reduces network resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We employ opportunistic forwarding that allows any relay to forward the overheard packet by scheduling or priority mechanism to prevent packets duplication between relays. Based on the figure 2, R2 can forward the packet after notice that R3 as the higher priority fails to deliver the packet. Therefore, we can achieve better reliability and throughput compared to fixed-path forwarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; 3.0.3  Bottle neck in opportunistic forwarding &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On-demand mechanisms create a long queue in the relay that causing a bottleneck problem. Furthermore, although opportunistic forwarding improves reliability between the sender and intermediate nodes, the transmission from intermediate nodes to the gateway may fail. The network coding approach not only increases the throughput but also increases the reliability by the concept of encoding and decoding multiple packets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3.0.4 Header overhead of RLNC in LPWA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the LoRaWAN study, the available LoRaWAN payload size varies between 51-250 Bytes with the header of 13-28 Bytes depends on the data-rate settings. Because RLNC has header overhead of n log&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; q bits, where n is the number of packets q is bit size in GF(2&lt;sup&gt;q&lt;/sup&gt;), we cannot implement RLNC directly in a massive IoT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, relay use GF(2&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;) to encode 100 packets with 30-bytes of packet size resulted in 50-bytes of header overhead in RLNC. Therefore, we adopt overhead header compression to solve packet size limitation in typical LPWA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">3.0.1 Preventing unnecessary forwarding</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/introduction.html">&lt;p&gt;LPWA technologies have gain more attention in various IoT service as it provides long transmission range between devices to devices with low power consumption. Compared to WiFi and Bluetooth that use 2.4-GHz for short-range com-munication, LPWA works on the  sub-GHz band, allowinglonger transmission range up to 20km in LOS. Although thedata rate is only 0.3 kbit/s to 50 kbit/s [1], it enough for IoT applications such as smart  city or telemetry services thatsend small packet over wider coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several LPWA technologies provided in the market based on licensed band  (LTE-M [2] and NB-IoT[3]) and unlicensed band(Sigfox[4] and LoRa[5]). Amongthem, LoRa or long-range radio, using a CSS (Chirp Spread Spectrum) modulation technique, is a popular LPWA radiotechnology adopted worldwide. LoRaWAN[6] is a MAClayer specification to build a network based on LoRa radio.As LoRaWan is an open standard, it becomes  popular because allowing researchers and developers to improve and modify the specification to their needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LoRaWAN adopts a one-hop star-of-star topology where an end-device transmits its packet to one or more gateways by LoRa modulation. Gateways linked with internet access to forward the packet to the network server via IP connection. To extend coverage in this simple topology, LoRaWAN utilize data-rate settings based on spreading factor SF (7-12) and Bandwidth BW (125 kHz, 250 kHz, and 500 kHz)[6]. As we increase the SF and decrease the BW, we can achieve longer coverage. However, this approach still suffers from coverage and reliability issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many researchers have studied LoRa performance under this topology. Field test in [7] shows that SF 12 is required to achieve 90\% of PDR in the coverage below 3 km. However, the scalability test in [8] tells that LoRa can only support 120 number of end-devices using this lower data rate settings. This low scalability performance is not surprising because LoRa transmission is based on the Aloha protocol.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">LPWA technologies have gain more attention in various IoT service as it provides long transmission range between devices to devices with low power consumption. Compared to WiFi and Bluetooth that use 2.4-GHz for short-range com-munication, LPWA works on the sub-GHz band, allowinglonger transmission range up to 20km in LOS. Although thedata rate is only 0.3 kbit/s to 50 kbit/s [1], it enough for IoT applications such as smart city or telemetry services thatsend small packet over wider coverage.</summary></entry></feed>