<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-26T16:55:04+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Abstract</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/abstract.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Abstract" /><published>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/abstract</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/abstract.html">&lt;p&gt;Low-power and wide-area (LPWA) technologies have become popular in various IoT services, mainly due to their low power and long communication range characteristics. However, LPWA still suffers from limited coverage and reliability issues, especially in an urban area where line-of-sight (LOS) communication is hard to achieve. The problem gets worsening in massive IoT environments as LPWA is vulnerable to the collision because of its long transmission time and unsophisticated Aloha-based MAC, which gets worse as the number of contending devices increases. Placing a relay forwarder between end-devices and gateway is introduced in some studies to extend coverage and to enhance communication reliability of LPWA. However, most previous studies adopt fixed-routing protocols for the relay. These fixed path approaches are vulnerable to the dynamicity of wireless propagation and make little use of multiple receptions, so it may easily lead to unnecessary forwarding that may raise collisions aggravating overall reliability and performance. We propose an opportunistic routing protocol for LPWA forwarders to make good use of multiple receptions. To suppress unnecessary forwarding, we adopt an on-demand/feedback message mechanism that is used by relays to determine whether to forward a packet or not. We also employ a network coding in generating forwarding packets in relays to increase the reliability and throughput further. As header overhead of network coding may exceed the size limitation of the LPWA packet, we use a header compression technique to encounter it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Index Terms—LPWA, unnecessary forwarding, on-demand, opportunistic forwarding, network coding, header overhead.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Low-power and wide-area (LPWA) technologies have become popular in various IoT services, mainly due to their low power and long communication range characteristics. However, LPWA still suffers from limited coverage and reliability issues, especially in an urban area where line-of-sight (LOS) communication is hard to achieve. The problem gets worsening in massive IoT environments as LPWA is vulnerable to the collision because of its long transmission time and unsophisticated Aloha-based MAC, which gets worse as the number of contending devices increases. Placing a relay forwarder between end-devices and gateway is introduced in some studies to extend coverage and to enhance communication reliability of LPWA. However, most previous studies adopt fixed-routing protocols for the relay. These fixed path approaches are vulnerable to the dynamicity of wireless propagation and make little use of multiple receptions, so it may easily lead to unnecessary forwarding that may raise collisions aggravating overall reliability and performance. We propose an opportunistic routing protocol for LPWA forwarders to make good use of multiple receptions. To suppress unnecessary forwarding, we adopt an on-demand/feedback message mechanism that is used by relays to determine whether to forward a packet or not. We also employ a network coding in generating forwarding packets in relays to increase the reliability and throughput further. As header overhead of network coding may exceed the size limitation of the LPWA packet, we use a header compression technique to encounter it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/introduction.html">&lt;p&gt;LPWA technologies have gain more attention in various IoT service as it provides long transmission range between devices to devices with low power consumption. Compared to WiFi and Bluetooth that use 2.4-GHz for short-range com-munication, LPWA works on the  sub-GHz band, allowinglonger transmission range up to 20km in LOS. Although thedata rate is only 0.3 kbit/s to 50 kbit/s [1], it enough for IoT applications such as smart  city or telemetry services thatsend small packet over wider coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several LPWA technologies provided in the market based on licensed band  (LTE-M [2] and NB-IoT[3]) and unlicensed band(Sigfox[4] and LoRa[5]). Amongthem, LoRa or long-range radio, using a CSS (Chirp Spread Spectrum) modulation technique, is a popular LPWA radiotechnology adopted worldwide. LoRaWAN[6] is a MAClayer specification to build a network based on LoRa radio.As LoRaWan is an open standard, it becomes  popular because allowing researchers and developers to improve and modify the specification to their needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LoRaWAN adopts a one-hop star-of-star topology where an end-device transmits its packet to one or more gateways by LoRa modulation. Gateways linked with internet access to forward the packet to the network server via IP connection. To extend coverage in this simple topology, LoRaWAN utilize data-rate settings based on spreading factor SF (7-12) and Bandwidth BW (125 kHz, 250 kHz, and 500 kHz)[6]. As we increase the SF and decrease the BW, we can achieve longer coverage. However, this approach still suffers from coverage and reliability issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many researchers have studied LoRa performance under this topology. Field test in [7] shows that SF 12 is required to achieve 90\% of PDR in the coverage below 3 km. However, the scalability test in [8] tells that LoRa can only support 120 number of end-devices using this lower data rate settings. This low scalability performance is not surprising because LoRa transmission is based on the Aloha protocol.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">LPWA technologies have gain more attention in various IoT service as it provides long transmission range between devices to devices with low power consumption. Compared to WiFi and Bluetooth that use 2.4-GHz for short-range com-munication, LPWA works on the sub-GHz band, allowinglonger transmission range up to 20km in LOS. Although thedata rate is only 0.3 kbit/s to 50 kbit/s [1], it enough for IoT applications such as smart city or telemetry services thatsend small packet over wider coverage.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Motivation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/motivation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Motivation" /><published>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/motivation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/05/04/motivation.html">&lt;h4&gt;3.0.1  Preventing unnecessary forwarding&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/master_thesis/assets/img/problem.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the side effects of the forwarder mechanism is unnecessary forwarding. Unnecessary forwarding uses network resources, which prevents the transmission from the legitimate packet. Thus, leading to performance degradation. As LPWA already offers broader coverage, the forwarder mechanism is only useful in certain conditions (see figure 1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, forwarders in LPWA should consider unnecessary forwarding if the gateway already receives the packet. To prevent this, we present a feedback messages like SACK acknowledgment contains all currently received packets to the relay. Therefore, relay only forward the missing packets after receiving the packets state from the network server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; 3.0.2  Reliability in uncertain wireless conditions &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/master_thesis/assets/img/wirelessconditions.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the wireless link is unstable, figure 2 shows possible transmission and reception between end-devices, relays, and gateway. Suppose that R1 and R2 receives the message, while R3 fails due to the propagation problem. If fixed-path routing assumes that R3 is the best forwarder, the packet cannot be delivered to the destination. Thus, we require re-transmission from the sender again. However, unnecessary retransmission reduces network resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We employ opportunistic forwarding that allows any relay to forward the overheard packet by scheduling or priority mechanism to prevent packets duplication between relays. Based on the figure 2, R2 can forward the packet after notice that R3 as the higher priority fails to deliver the packet. Therefore, we can achieve better reliability and throughput compared to fixed-path forwarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; 3.0.3  Bottle neck in opportunistic forwarding &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On-demand mechanisms create a long queue in the relay that causing a bottleneck problem. Furthermore, although opportunistic forwarding improves reliability between the sender and intermediate nodes, the transmission from intermediate nodes to the gateway may fail. The network coding approach not only increases the throughput but also increases the reliability by the concept of encoding and decoding multiple packets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3.0.4 Header overhead of RLNC in LPWA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the LoRaWAN study, the available LoRaWAN payload size varies between 51-250 Bytes with the header of 13-28 Bytes depends on the data-rate settings. Because RLNC has header overhead of n log&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; q bits, where n is the number of packets q is bit size in GF(2&lt;sup&gt;q&lt;/sup&gt;), we cannot implement RLNC directly in a massive IoT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, relay use GF(2&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;) to encode 100 packets with 30-bytes of packet size resulted in 50-bytes of header overhead in RLNC. Therefore, we adopt overhead header compression to solve packet size limitation in typical LPWA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">3.0.1 Preventing unnecessary forwarding</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Evaluation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/04/25/evaluation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Evaluation" /><published>2020-04-25T17:26:41+09:00</published><updated>2020-04-25T17:26:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/04/25/evaluation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/04/25/evaluation.html">&lt;h4&gt;1. Studying LoRaWAN Reliability&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/master_thesis/assets/img/LBTstudy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evaluation shows that applying capture effect increase LoRa’s reliability. Furthermore, LBT-ALOHA also shows better reliability than Pure-ALOHA around 12%. LBT-ALOHA reduces collision by scanning the medium before transmission. Thus, prevent end-devices from transmitting a packet at the same time. Based on this result, we apply LBT-ALOHA with capture effect for evaluating FO and FONC approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2. Increasing LoRaWAN Coverage &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/master_thesis/assets/img/evalcoverage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the FDR scenario, all packet forwarding mechanisms achieve more than 90% of PDR, although we increase the number of end-devices up to 1200. However, both FO and FONC perform better with around 99% of PDR compared to FP, with only around 92% of PDR. On the other hand, reliability result in SDR scenario for all mechanism is decreasing. Even when SDR scenario is used to serve hundreds of end-devices, it only gets reliability results around 88%. This result shows that the difference in transmission time between SDR and FDR scenario affect the collision probability. As more end-devices join in the contentions, LoRaWAN performance degrades faster. Especially when most of end-devices use SDR settings to provide wider range. Hence, we conclude that single star-of-stars topology in massive IoT has scalability issues because it has to rely on slow data-rate to support transmission from far away end-devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3. Improving LoRaWAN Scalability &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/master_thesis/assets/img/adr.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ADR mechanism usually tends to maximize the data rate configurations to achieve faster transmission time. However, faster data rate settings increase receiver sensitivity that decreases transmission coverage. Consequently, we may not get the full benefit over multi-reception if end-device only reaches a single relay. In this paper, we present ADR comparison based on the strong/maximum RSSI and weak/minimum RSSI of relay candidates to study the best data-rate settings. Relay candidates are selected based on the possible relays that can be reached in SDR transmission&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the results, both minADR and maxADR outperform SDR with slower performance degradation. The minADR shows better reliability compared to maxADR for below 600 number of end-devices. For FO and FONC, minADR can achieve more than 90% of PDR when serving hundreds of end-devices. It shows that multi-reception has a contribution to increasing the LoRaWAN reliability.  However, as we increase the number of end-devices, higher collisions cannot be avoided. On the other hand, maxADR shows better performance than minADR for a large number of end-devices. MaxADR on FO and FONC also shows more stable performance and degrade slower than maxADR on FP. It also shows the benefit over multi-reception because several end-devices still reach both relay candidates, although using maxADR approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;4. Preventing Unnecessary Forwarding&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/master_thesis/assets/img/unnecessaryre.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/master_thesis/assets/img/unnecessaryam.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons behind the performance degradation in fixed-path are unnecessary forwarding. Both FO and FONC succeed in suppressing unnecessary transmission because of the feedback-based mechanism. Moreover, both relays can coordinate each other to suppress the duplicate packet between relay forwarding. On the other hand, fixed-path forwarding suffers from performance degradation because of packet collisions, caused by unnecessary forwarding. In FDR scenario, the number of unnecessary forwarding is stable around 38%-44% because of low packet collision. If we look at the reliability performance and the number of unnecessary forwarding, we can assume that fixed-path relay forwarding may increase the reliability by unnecessary forwarding. However, evaluation in SDR scenario shows low performance. The number of unnecessary forwarding also degrades because of packet collision.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">1. Studying LoRaWAN Reliability</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conculusions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/04/24/conclusions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conculusions" /><published>2020-04-24T17:26:41+09:00</published><updated>2020-04-24T17:26:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/04/24/conclusions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/bookmark/2020/04/24/conclusions.html">&lt;p&gt;In this thesis, we present feedback based opportunistic forwarding (FO) and feedback based opportunistic forwarding with network coding (FONC) as a forwarder mechanism to increase the LoRaWAN coverage, reliability, and scalability with better transmission efficiency. We propose this approach to overcome the limitation of one-hop star-of-stars in providing scalable long-range communication. Compared to the previous studies, we consider unnecessary forwarding as one of the drawbacks of a typical relay forwarder. In our mechanism, relay only forward when the packet is lost due to coverage limitation or obstacle problem (both temporal and permanent) that blocked a direct transmission to the gateway. 
Both FO and FONC show better reliability performance in increasing network coverage and suppressing unnecessary transmission compared to fixed-path forwarding. The multi-reception approach, feedback message, and network coding is the main mechanism to improve reliability. Whereas, the feedback approach prevents unnecessary forwarding. In fast data rate settings, the reliability is still stable around 99% for traffic load G=2.1 (1200 number of end-devices). On the other hand, the performance in slow data rate degrades faster. We present minimum RSSI and maximum RSSI based adaptive data rate (ADR) to overcome the scalability issue in LoRa network. The result shows that minADR selection gives better performance for end-devices below 600 owing to exploitation on multi-reception. Otherwise, maxADR is preferred because the result is more stable above 70% although we increase the end-device up to 1200.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In this thesis, we present feedback based opportunistic forwarding (FO) and feedback based opportunistic forwarding with network coding (FONC) as a forwarder mechanism to increase the LoRaWAN coverage, reliability, and scalability with better transmission efficiency. We propose this approach to overcome the limitation of one-hop star-of-stars in providing scalable long-range communication. Compared to the previous studies, we consider unnecessary forwarding as one of the drawbacks of a typical relay forwarder. In our mechanism, relay only forward when the packet is lost due to coverage limitation or obstacle problem (both temporal and permanent) that blocked a direct transmission to the gateway. Both FO and FONC show better reliability performance in increasing network coverage and suppressing unnecessary transmission compared to fixed-path forwarding. The multi-reception approach, feedback message, and network coding is the main mechanism to improve reliability. Whereas, the feedback approach prevents unnecessary forwarding. In fast data rate settings, the reliability is still stable around 99% for traffic load G=2.1 (1200 number of end-devices). On the other hand, the performance in slow data rate degrades faster. We present minimum RSSI and maximum RSSI based adaptive data rate (ADR) to overcome the scalability issue in LoRa network. The result shows that minADR selection gives better performance for end-devices below 600 owing to exploitation on multi-reception. Otherwise, maxADR is preferred because the result is more stable above 70% although we increase the end-device up to 1200.</summary></entry></feed>