<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-05T01:14:50+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Abstract</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/jekyll/update/2020/05/04/abstract.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Abstract" /><published>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/jekyll/update/2020/05/04/abstract</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/jekyll/update/2020/05/04/abstract.html">&lt;p&gt;Abstract—Low-power and wide-area (LPWA) technologies have become popular in various IoT services, mainly due to their low powerand long communication range characteristics. However, LPWA still suffers from limited coverage and reliability issues, especially in anurban area where line-of-sight (LOS) communication is hard to achieve. The problem gets worsening in massive IoT environments asLPWA is vulnerable to the collision because of its long transmission time and unsophisticated Aloha-based MAC, which gets worse asthe number of contending devices increases. Placing a relay forwarder between end-devices and gateway is introduced in some studiesto extend coverage and to enhance communication reliability of LPWA. However, most previous studies adopt fixed-routing protocolsfor the relay. These fixed path approaches are vulnerable to the dynamicity of wireless propagation and make little use of multiplereceptions, so it may easily lead to unnecessary forwarding that may raise collisions aggravating overall reliability and performance.We propose an opportunistic routing protocol for LPWA forwarders to make good use of multiple receptions. To suppress unnecessaryforwarding, we adopt an on-demand/feedback message mechanism that is used by relays to determine whether to forward a packet ornot. We also employ a network coding in generating forwarding packets in relays to increase the reliability and throughput further. Asheader overhead of network coding may exceed the size limitation of the LPWA packet, we use a header compression technique toencounter it. Our on-demand opportunistic with network coding (OODC) forwarding show doubled reliability improvement compared tofixed-path forwarding according to our simulation results. More specifically, with normalized traffic loadG=2, the OODC achieves 78%of PDR, where a fixed-path forwarding only 50% of PDR in an adaptive data-rate scenario. We also found that the proposed solutionminimizes unnecessary transmissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Index Terms—LPWA, unnecessary forwarding, on-demand, opportunistic forwarding, network coding, header overhead.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Abstract—Low-power and wide-area (LPWA) technologies have become popular in various IoT services, mainly due to their low powerand long communication range characteristics. However, LPWA still suffers from limited coverage and reliability issues, especially in anurban area where line-of-sight (LOS) communication is hard to achieve. The problem gets worsening in massive IoT environments asLPWA is vulnerable to the collision because of its long transmission time and unsophisticated Aloha-based MAC, which gets worse asthe number of contending devices increases. Placing a relay forwarder between end-devices and gateway is introduced in some studiesto extend coverage and to enhance communication reliability of LPWA. However, most previous studies adopt fixed-routing protocolsfor the relay. These fixed path approaches are vulnerable to the dynamicity of wireless propagation and make little use of multiplereceptions, so it may easily lead to unnecessary forwarding that may raise collisions aggravating overall reliability and performance.We propose an opportunistic routing protocol for LPWA forwarders to make good use of multiple receptions. To suppress unnecessaryforwarding, we adopt an on-demand/feedback message mechanism that is used by relays to determine whether to forward a packet ornot. We also employ a network coding in generating forwarding packets in relays to increase the reliability and throughput further. Asheader overhead of network coding may exceed the size limitation of the LPWA packet, we use a header compression technique toencounter it. Our on-demand opportunistic with network coding (OODC) forwarding show doubled reliability improvement compared tofixed-path forwarding according to our simulation results. More specifically, with normalized traffic loadG=2, the OODC achieves 78%of PDR, where a fixed-path forwarding only 50% of PDR in an adaptive data-rate scenario. We also found that the proposed solutionminimizes unnecessary transmissions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/jekyll/update/2020/05/04/introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T17:26:41+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/jekyll/update/2020/05/04/introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/jekyll/update/2020/05/04/introduction.html">&lt;p&gt;LPWA technologies have gain more attention in variousIoT service as it provides long transmission range betweendevices to devices with low power consumption. Comparedto WiFi and Bluetooth that use 2.4-GHz for short-range com-munication,  LPWA  works  on  the  sub-GHz  band,  allowinglonger transmission range up to 20km in LOS. Although thedata rate is only 0.3 kbit/s to 50 kbit/s [1], it enough for IoTapplications  such  as  smart  city  or  telemetry  services  thatsend small packet over wider coverage.There  are  several  LPWA  technologies  provided  in  themarket  based  on  licensed  band  (LTE-M  [2]  and  NB-IoT[3])  and  unlicensed  band(Sigfox[4]  and  LoRa[5]).  Amongthem, LoRa or long-range radio, using a CSS (Chirp SpreadSpectrum) modulation technique, is a popular LPWA radiotechnology  adopted  worldwide.  LoRaWAN[6]  is  a  MAClayer specification to build a network based on LoRa radio.As  LoRaWan  is  an  open  standard,  it  becomes  popular  be-cause allowing researchers and developers to improve andmodify the specification to their needs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">LPWA technologies have gain more attention in variousIoT service as it provides long transmission range betweendevices to devices with low power consumption. Comparedto WiFi and Bluetooth that use 2.4-GHz for short-range com-munication, LPWA works on the sub-GHz band, allowinglonger transmission range up to 20km in LOS. Although thedata rate is only 0.3 kbit/s to 50 kbit/s [1], it enough for IoTapplications such as smart city or telemetry services thatsend small packet over wider coverage.There are several LPWA technologies provided in themarket based on licensed band (LTE-M [2] and NB-IoT[3]) and unlicensed band(Sigfox[4] and LoRa[5]). Amongthem, LoRa or long-range radio, using a CSS (Chirp SpreadSpectrum) modulation technique, is a popular LPWA radiotechnology adopted worldwide. LoRaWAN[6] is a MAClayer specification to build a network based on LoRa radio.As LoRaWan is an open standard, it becomes popular be-cause allowing researchers and developers to improve andmodify the specification to their needs.</summary></entry></feed>